Guide to the William Hemsley Emory Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- 1822-1858 April, Series I; 5; (12 boxes)
  - Receipts for U.S. property returned and other receipts re: U.S. property, 1847-48 (Box 10, Folder 109)
  - Military orders, 1848 Dec-1849 Dec (Box 10, Folder 110)
  - Military orders book in which orders concerning the Boundary Commission by John B. Weller were copied; other information on Commission, 1849 Apr-1850 Jul (Box 10, Folder 111)
  - Military orders, 1850 Jan-Jul (Box 10, Folder 112)
  - Military orders and instructions, 1852-55 (Box 10, Folder 113)
  - Minutes of meetings, agreements and other documents relating to the Joint Commission (U.S. and Mexico), 1850-55 (Box 10, Folder 114)
  - Memoranda and lists relating to instruments and apparatus for the Boundary Commission, 1849 Jan-Dec (Box 10, Folder 115)
  - Lists of provision returns, 1849 Nov-Dec (Box 10, Folder 116)
  - Reports of return of escort to Boundary Commission, 1849 Jun-1850 Jan (Box 10, Folder 117)
  - Morning reports, 1849 Sep-1849 Dec 23-1850 Jan 31 (Box 10, Folder 118)
  - Papers concerning equipment, supplies, and personnel for Boundary Commission, 1850 Apr-Nov, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 119)
  - Papers concerning equipment, supplies, and personnel for Boundary Commission, 1851 Jan-Dec (Box 10, Folder 120)
  - Papers concerning equipment, supplies, and personnel for Boundary Commission, 1852 Jan-Dec (Box 11, Folder 121)
  - Papers concerning equipment, supplies, and personnel for Boundary Commission, 1853 Mar-Aug (Box 11, Folder 122)
  - Papers concerning equipment, supplies, and personnel for Boundary Commission, 1853 Sep-Dec, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 123)
  - Papers concerning equipment, supplies, and personnel for Boundary Commission, 1854 Jan (Box 11, Folder 124)
  - Papers concerning equipment, supplies, and personnel for Boundary Commission, 1854 Jun-Aug (Box 11, Folder 125)
  - Papers concerning equipment, supplies, and personnel for Boundary Commission, 1854 Sep-Dec, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 126)
  - Papers concerning equipment, supplies, and personnel for Boundary Commission, 1855 Jan-Dec (Box 11, Folder 127)
  - Papers concerning equipment, supplies, and personnel for Boundary Commission, 1856-57, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 128)
  - Records of checks drawn on the account of the Boundary Commission, 1856 Feb-1857 Oct (Box 11, Folder 129)
  - Records of Boards of Survey, 1851-54 (Box 11, Folder 130)
  - Agreements, certificates, and other legal documents, 1850-53 (Box 11, Folder 131)
  - Agreements, certificates, and other legal documents, 1854-56 (Box 11, Folder 132)
  - Notes on scientific observations, surveys, and calculations, 1845-57 (Box 12, Folder 133)
  - Maps (Box 12, Folder 133)
    Scope and Contents
    Also stored in: Oversize, box 15, folder 156
  - Notebook containing astronomical data and tables (Box 12, Folder 134)
  - Fragments of manuscripts of Emory's reports on the Boundary Survey, 1857 (Box 12, Folder 135)
  - Memoranda, notes, estimates, receipts, and other documents relating to the printing of the Report of the Boundary Commission and the engraving of plates, 1854-57 (Box 12, Folder 136)
  - Personal and financial records, commissions and memorabilia, 1826-57 (Box 12, Folder 137)
    Stored also in: Oversize, box 16, folder 157
  - Clippings, 1851-54 (Box 12, Folder 138)
  - Miscellaneous items, 1851-57 (Box 12, Folder 139)
- 1858 August-1886, Series II; 0.5; (2 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1858 Aug-1859 Jun (Box 13, Folder 140)
  - Correspondence, 1861 (Box 13, Folder 141)
  - Correspondence, 1862 (Box 13, Folder 142)
  - Correspondence, 1863 Feb-May (Box 13, Folder 143)
  - Correspondence, 1863 Jun (Box 13, Folder 144)
  - Correspondence, 1863 Jul-Dec (Box 13, Folder 145)
  - Correspondence, 1864 Jan-Apr (Box 13, Folder 146)
  - Correspondence, 1864 May-Dec (Box 13, Folder 147)
  - Correspondence, 1865 (Box 13, Folder 148)
  - Correspondence, 1866 (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - Correspondence, 1867-97, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 150)
  - Receipts, statements, and accounts for the Recruiting Account, 1861 Jun-1862 Mar (Box 13, Folder 151)
  - Orders, memoranda, notes, and other documents relating to Emory's service stationed at the Department of the Gulf (Attack on Port Hudson, Defense of New Orleans, Lafourche Crossing), 1862 Dec-1863 Jul (Box 14, Folder 152)
  - Orders, memoranda, notes, and other documents relating to the Red River Campaign, 1863 Dec-1864 Jul (Box 14, Folder 153)
  - Orders, memoranda, notes, and other documents relating to the Shenandoah Campaign and further assignments in the Shenandoah Valley and the Department of West Virginia, 1864 Aug-1866 Jan (Box 14, Folder 154)
  - Personal financial records and memorabilia, 1865-84 (Box 14, Folder 155)
  - Draft for chapter "Organization of Armies", 1886, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 155)
- Oversize
  Oversize contains material from series I, arranged in box order.
  - Notes on scientific observations, surveys, and calculations; maps; personal and financial records, commissions, and memorabilia, 1826-57 (Box 15)